<TextFlow xmlns='http://ns.adobe.com/textLayout/2008' fontFamily='Arial' fontSize='14' header='Use your dictionary to check your work'>
		
<p><span fontWeight='bold'>Using your dictionary.</span></p>
<p>The main part of the dictionary can help you choose the right language to use. You can also use it to check that you have used the correct grammar and spelling.</p>
<p>Ask yourself:</p>
<p><span fontWeight='bold'>Have I used the right word?</span></p>
<p>The dictionary has notes and illustrations that explain confusing words, for example <span color='#0000FF'>borrow/lend</span> (look at <span color='#0000FF'>borrow</span>) and <span color='#0000FF'>sympathetic/nice</span> (look at <span color='#0000FF'>sympathetic</span>). Sometimes learners choose the wrong word because they translate from their own language. Check any words that you are not sure about.</p>
<p><span fontWeight='bold'>What about language and style?</span></p>
<p>Have you used any words that are too formal or informal in this type of writing? Check in the dictionary if you’re not sure. The labels <span fontStyle="italic">formal</span>, <span fontStyle="italic">informal</span>, <span fontStyle="italic">spoken</span> and <span fontStyle="italic">slang</span> will help you.</p>
<p><span fontWeight='bold'>Have I used the same word or phrase too many times?</span></p>
<p>Try to find different ways to say things. Use your dictionary and to see if there is a synonym for a word you use a lot.</p>
<p><span fontWeight='bold'>Have I used the right words together?</span></p>	
<p>Is it <span fontStyle="italic">make homework</span> or <span fontStyle="italic">do homework</span>? Look up the main word in the dictionary (<span color='#0000FF'>homework</span>) and see which word it is used with in the examples.</p>
<p><span fontWeight='bold'>What about prepositions?</span></p>
<p>Is it <span fontStyle="italic">close to</span> or <span fontStyle="italic">close from</span>? Check prepositions after nouns, verbs or adjectives very carefully.</p>
<p><span fontWeight='bold'>Have I used the correct verb patterns? </span></p>
<p>Is it <span fontStyle="italic">enjoy to do something</span> or <span fontStyle="italic">enjoy doing something</span>? Look at the example sentences for <span color='#0000FF'>enjoy</span>.</p>
<p><span fontWeight='bold'>What about spelling?</span></p>
<p>Check the spelling of plurals, past tenses,</p>
<p>-ing forms and comparative and superlative adjectives and adverbs. Words that are similar to words in your language may be spelled differently. You can find the names of countries, cities and nationalities in the list at the back of the dictionary or on your CD-ROM.</p>
<p><span fontWeight='bold'>Is the grammar correct?</span></p>
<p>Have you checked if the nouns are countable or uncountable? Are the verbs irregular? There is a list of irregular verbs at the back of the dictionary that will help you.</p>
<p><span fontWeight='bold'>Make your own checklist.</span></p>
<p>Look carefully at the mistakes your teacher marks in your written work and make a list of the mistakes you often make. Use this list to check each piece of work you do – before you give it to the teacher.</p>
	


	
</TextFlow>
